<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Infinite Possibilities</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/mySite/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Dare to Dream</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 12:03:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>New Manager Surprises</title>
		<link>/2022/07/23/new-manager-surprises/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 09:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently, I spoke to a group of new managers (mostly) and people who&#8217;ve transitioned from a Product/Program Management role about surprises that new people managers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Recently, I spoke to a group of new managers (mostly) and people who&#8217;ve transitioned from a Product/Program Management role about surprises that new people managers encounter. This talk was a drill down (albeit with a slight improvisation) on the research conducted by <a href="https://hbr.org/search?term=michael%20e.%20porter">Michael E. Porter,</a><a href="https://hbr.org/search?term=jay%20w.%20lorsch">Jay W. Lorsch,</a> and <a href="https://hbr.org/search?term=nitin%20nohria">Nitin Nohria</a> which was outlined in their 2004 HBR article titled <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hbr.org/2004/10/seven-surprises-for-new-ceos" target="_blank"><em>Seven Surprises for New CEOs </em></a>. While the article dates back to 2004, the findings remain relevant even today.</p>



<p>While the original content was written with CEOs in mind, I&#8217;ve adapted that to managers at all levels given the audience of this networking session.</p>



<hr class="flaired">


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1-1024x663.png" alt="" class="wp-image-280" width="628" height="406" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1-1024x663.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1-300x194.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1-768x497.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1.png 1307w" sizes="(max-width: 628px) 100vw, 628px" /></figure></div>


<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong><em>Management</em></strong> is both  <strong><em>Art</em></strong> and <strong><em>Science</em></strong>. It is <em>science</em> because there&#8217;s systemic study material, repeatable processes, and causality that can be learnt. It&#8217;s an Art because management requires a considerable amount of skill, practice, creativity and Individual application &#8211; what works for one may not work for another person. It&#8217;s therefore imperative to understand what one can expect as they embark on their management journey and chart a course for success. </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s start with what new managers may find surprising as they embark on their management journey</p>



<br style="clear:left"><hr class="flaired">



<h3>You <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">can&#8217;t</mark> do everything</h3>



<p>As you enter management, you have to get comfortable with the feeling that you can&#8217;t be directly involved with everything that&#8217;s happening in your project / organization, yet you are fully accountable for outcomes &amp; results. This is in stark contrast to back when you were an individual contributor and now your time will be needed in more places than you can imagine.</p>



<p>To avoid/overcome problems with this surprise, you have to learn to</p>



<ol><li>Effectively <a href="#delegation">Delegate</a> to your direct reports and trust them</li><li>Manage your <a href="#timemanagement">time efficiently</a></li></ol>



<h3>You <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">can&#8217;t</mark> always tell people what to do</h3>



<p>You cannot micromanage every decision by telling people how to do things. Like Steve jobs said &#8220;<code><em>It doesn't make sense to hire smart people and then tell them what to to , We hire smart people so they can tell us what to do</em></code><strong><em>.</em>”</strong> We should enable people by providing the right amount of clarity on the needs and expectations around outcomes/ results and provide autonomy to execute.</p>



<p>Practice the following and you&#8217;ll steer clear and learn more</p>



<ul><li>Provide Clarity<ul><li>Set Vision &amp; Standards </li><li>Define operating principles (review cadence, stakeholder communication, cost etc)</li><li>Learn from mistakes (remember that we all learn from our mistakes, so create and embrace a culture where people can freely talk about failures and learnings from them)</li></ul></li><li>Avoid Decision Bottlenecks<ul><li>Share power and make people part of the decision making process. This can hugely improve trust.</li><li>Encourage the culture of calculated risk taking.</li><li>Learn and make use of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.guru99.com/decision-making-tools.html" target="_blank">Decision making tools</a>.</li></ul></li></ul>



<h3>You <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">won&#8217;t</mark> always know what&#8217;s going on</h3>



<p>As a manager, you&#8217;ll have a lot of things going on around you (meetings, stakeholder management, planning, people issues, budgeting, hiring, performance management and tons more). Amidst all of that, it&#8217;s very difficult to keep track of every aspect of what&#8217;s happening. People won&#8217;t immediately be willing to give you the bad news, so by the time it gets to you, it may be late or have some glossy touches added.</p>



<p>But to manage effectively, you need to stay on top of things and be in the loop. Here are some thoughts on what can help you get there.</p>



<ul><li>Identify ways to collect as much information as possible about what&#8217;s happening in the team from different sources.<ul><li>Practice <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Management_by_wandering_around" target="_blank">Management by walking around (MBWA)</a></li><li>Another alternate is <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemba#:~:text=The%20Gemba%20Walk%20is%20an,results%20or%20make%20superficial%20comments." target="_blank">Gemba walk</a>, popularized by Toyota, where you walk to the place where the action happens, ask questions and learn.</li><li>Have skip level 1:1s and team meetings.</li></ul></li><li>Build strong partnerships with all your stakeholders<ul><li>Talk to your peers, customers, cross functional leaders, HR partners etc. This will give you a rounded perspective of what&#8217;s happening.</li></ul></li></ul>



<h3>You are always being <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">watched</mark>!</h3>



<p>I don&#8217;t&#8217; say this as something to be scared about, but as a manager/leader of the organization, you are always sending a message. The way you speak (or don’t speak!), your body language, choice of words, way to write, everything starts to matter now. People will try to read between lines and there are chances you can be misinterpreted.</p>



<p>To avoid potential issues because of this, try to</p>



<ul><li>Lead by example. Role model the behavior you would like to see in your team members. Your actions will soon be replicated in your team, so use it to your advantage.</li><li>Communicate clearly and ask for clarifications. Don&#8217;t assume people understood what you said.</li><li>Improve your self-awareness and Emotional Quotient</li><li>This is a continuous learning process, so you will have Blind spots. Get an <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://actionbuddy.io/blog/accountability-partner#:~:text=An%20accountability%20partner%20is%20someone,to%20stick%20to%20their%20commitments." target="_blank">accountability partner</a> who can help provide feedback.</li></ul>



<h3>Organizational Politics is <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">real</mark>!</h3>



<p>Not all politics is bad. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://opentext.wsu.edu/organizational-behavior/chapter/13-4-organizational-politics/" target="_blank">Organizational politics</a> is real and how well you deal with it will also define your success trajectory. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hbr.org/2017/04/the-4-types-of-organizational-politics" target="_blank">Studies show</a> that individuals with political skills tend to have a greater impact on organizational outcomes. Understanding and navigating organizational politics and improving your influencing authority will provide better outcomes for your teams.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-301" width="333" height="303" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/image.png 329w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/image-300x273.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 333px) 100vw, 333px" /><figcaption>Credits: Mindtools &#8211; <a href="https://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/newPPM_07.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stakeholder Analysis</a></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Here are some thoughts about how to handle this</p>



<ul><li>Be Politically Savvy. What this means is that you are aware of what’s going on around you, you’re paying attention to the dynamics, paying attention to who has power and influence, and what the culture of your organization is, and you are positioning yourself successfully with all that information.</li><li>Build and leverage your network.</li><li>Understand your stakeholders and map them. <em>Power/interest grid for stakeholder prioritization</em> on the left can be one useful technique.</li></ul>



<div style="clear:right"></div>



<h3>You are still only <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">Human</mark>!</h3>



<p>You must remember that your position as a manager/leader does not automatically make you better or more capable. Like everyone else, you will learn from experience and the many mistakes that&#8217;ll provide important lessons along the way. However, as a manager, you have more accountability and responsibility, and how you role model your behaviors will be replicated.</p>



<p>It is essential to keep the following things in mind as you embark on your management/leadership journey.</p>



<ul><li>Your Work/Life balance is extremely important and how you manage it will be emulated by your team. Remember your mood will affect your team&#8217;s mood as well.<ul><li>A friend once gave me this priority list that I strive to follow &#8211; Health -> Family -> Relationships -> Work</li></ul></li><li>Being vulnerable and asking for help will improve trust with your teams and you&#8217;ll achieve more together.</li><li>Be Thankful, stay humble and praise generously.</li><li>Get a mentor/coach who can help you along the way and share their learnings.</li></ul>



<br><hr class="flaired">



<h4>Appendix</h4>



<ul id="delegation"><li><strong><em>Delegation</em></strong> is the assignment of authority to another person (normally from a manager to a subordinate) to carry out specific activities. It is the process of distributing and entrusting work to another person, and therefore one of the core concepts of management leadership. The process involves managers deciding which work they should do themselves and which work should be delegated to others for completion.[1] From a managerial standpoint, delegation involves shifting project responsibility to team members, giving them the opportunity to finalize the work product effectively, with minimal intervention. The opposite of effective delegation is micromanagement, where a manager provides too much input, direction, and review of delegated work. Delegation empowers a subordinate to make decisions. It is a shifting of decision-making authority as well as responsibility for the results from one organisational level to another lower one. However, a certain level of accountability for the outcome of the work does remain with the person who delegated the work to begin with.<ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://online.hbs.edu/blog/post/how-to-delegate-effectively" target="_blank">How to Delegate Effectively</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/shreyas/status/1401615513998950401" target="_blank">Radical Delegation by Shreyas Doshi</a></li></ul></li></ul>



<ul id="timemanagement"><li><strong><em>Time Management</em></strong><ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://todoist.com/productivity-methods/eisenhower-matrix" target="_blank">Eisenhower Matrix</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.business2community.com/strategy/6-time-management-techniques-to-help-you-get-everything-done-02166826" target="_blank">Other Techniques</a></li></ul></li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 22/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/22/friday-musings-22-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 05:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’m reading. How can I become a Director? &#160;– A very well written piece by Guru Bhat on what it takes to become a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-3 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-1 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Articles I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-can-i-become-director-guru-bhat/">How can I become a Director? </a>&nbsp;– A very well written piece by Guru Bhat on what it takes to become a director. Eloquent as always, Guru hits the bulls eye on some key attributes that everyone should aspire to attain if they are on a quest for this title. I’ve been fortunate to learn by experience how “Bias for Action” can be a key differentiator in creating value for our stakeholders.</p>



<h3><strong><em>What worries me!</em></strong></h3>



<p>It’s hard to miss the series of natural calamities rocking the already pandemic struck world right now. From the <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2022/07/19/google_oracle_cloud/?mc_cid=1674b3c928&amp;mc_eid=2b8cf1fb98">extreme heat waves in UK &amp; Europe</a> to <a href="https://www.thenationalnews.com/world/asia/2022/07/21/indias-monsoon-havoc-a-result-of-climate-change-experts-say/">Cloud bursts and Flash floods in India</a>, It’s time each one of us do our part to slow down climate change. <a href="https://medium.com/@cinthia.espino/why-is-0-5-c-so-important-3961b9989387">Read this</a> if you want to know what a 0.5° Celsius change could mean to earth and <a href="https://coastal.climatecentral.org/map/10/72.9068/18.9721/?theme=sea_level_rise&amp;map_type=year&amp;basemap=roadmap&amp;contiguous=true&amp;elevation_model=best_available&amp;forecast_year=2040&amp;pathway=ssp3rcp70&amp;percentile=p50&amp;refresh=true&amp;return_level=return_level_0&amp;rl_model=gtsr&amp;slr_model=ipcc_2021_med">see these projections</a> of cities that would be under water if the sea-levels continues to rise.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://tim.blog/2022/06/28/edward-o-thorp-2/">Master Investor Ed Thorp on How to think for yourself and many more topics</a> – This is a long format podcast but there&#8217;s some invaluable takeaways from Ed&#8217;s experience. I&#8217;m a big fan of the Tim&#8217;s questions to his guests and the insights that he gleans from them. What particularly excited me in this podcast was how Ed was leveraging the power of compounding in anything he does, be it investing, loosing weight, forming habits, learning new things etc. Really loved the concept of &#8220;scrap time&#8221; and hope to incorporate in my life as well.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://wasp-lang.dev/blog/2022/06/24/ML-code-gen-vs-coding-by-hand-future">ML Codegen Vs Coding by Hand</a> – In the previous musings I shared about auto code-gen and it got me intrigued into aspects that are debatable and why we should tread with care. This post explores some of this nuance and has a good further reading on other thoughts on the same topic as well</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>If you really think that the environment is less important than the economy, try holding your breath while you count your money</p><cite>Guy McPherson</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-2 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 15/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/15/friday-musings-15-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Article I’m reading. Injections that edit Genes to stop diseases! – I’m filled with both hope and fear when I read articles like this. While [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-6 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-4 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Article I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/07/12/1055773/crispr-gene-editing-cholesterol/">Injections that edit Genes to stop diseases!</a> – I’m filled with both hope and fear when I read articles like this. While this has the power to save millions of people, what stops someone from using the same tech for nefarious purposes.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Places I’ve travelled.</em></strong></h3>



<p>I was in Bangalore this week meeting my colleagues in-person in office and wow, what a week it was. While there’s comfort &amp; some flexibility in working from home, nothing can beat the in-person collaboration and getting things done quickly. For me, Video calls somehow reduce the personal &amp; emotional side of the conversation. Looking forward to many more such visits and catching up with my people!</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/why-youre-smarter-than-you-think/">Why you&#8217;re smarter than you think!</a> – From the Hidden brain show notes – “<em>From the time we are schoolchildren, we are ranked and sorted based on how smart we are. But what if our assumptions about intelligence limit our potential? This week, psychologist Scott Barry Kaufman proposes a more expansive notion of what it means to be “smart</em>&#8220;.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><em> </em></strong><a href="https://simonwillison.net/2022/Jul/9/gpt-3-explain-code/">Can GPT-3 explain how code works?</a> – I was amazed by the extent to which models like GPT-3 &amp; OpenAI Codex are getting increasingly efficient at writing code. Makes me wonder when we’d land in a situation where we no longer hire programmers</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>You wouldn&#8217;t worry so much about what others think of you if you realized how seldom they do</p><cite>Elenaor Roosevelt</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-5 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 08/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/08/friday-musings-08-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 04:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Article I’m reading. How to work with someone you can’t stand – “Like it or not, your job and reputation can rely on an ability [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div class="wp-container-9 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-7 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<h3><strong><em>Article I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90596343/how-to-work-with-someone-you-cant-stand">How to work with someone you can’t stand</a> –</strong>  “<em>Like it or not, your job and reputation can rely on an ability to get along with others.”</em> Valdes-Dapena says there are steps you can take to make the situation more bearable.”</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2A7mblg5UKc">Trying to Land a Plane (to Prove a Point)</a> &nbsp;</strong>&#8211; <em>I’ve always been intrigued by Dunning-Krueger effect &amp; Imposter Syndrome and how it pretty much manifests in everybody. Personally I’m starting to get comfortable saying “I Don’t Know” and “I need help” more often these days.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://freakonomics.com/podcast/how-simple-is-too-simple/"><strong>How simple is too simple</strong></a> –<em> In this episode of “No Stupid Questions”, Angela Duckworth and Stephen Dubner discuss the obsession humans have with magic bullet solutions and why there are no simple answers.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.morling.dev/blog/whats-in-a-good-error-message/">What&#8217;s in a good Error Message</a>? </strong>– <em>Extremely important for all engineering devs and leads reviewing code. Both the article and the discussion/comments following it has several extremely using nuggets we should think about.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Quote I’m thinking about!</em></strong> </h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“What is Common Sense, isn’t Common Practice” – Stephen Covey</p></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-8 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 01/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/01/friday-musings-01-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Books I’m (re)reading. I’ve picked up “Radical Candor” by Kim Scott again. IMO, it’s one of the must reads for anyone picking up Management for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-12 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-10 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Books I’m (re)reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p>I’ve picked up <a href="https://www.radicalcandor.com/the-book/">“Radical Candor” by Kim Scott</a> again. IMO, it’s one of the must reads for anyone picking up Management for their career. It shows managers how to be successful while retaining their humanity, finding meaning in their job, and creating an environment where people both love their work and their colleagues</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEENEFaVUzU">The Last Human! &#8211; A Glimpse into&nbsp; the Far Future</a> &nbsp;&#8211; I’ve always been mesmerized by Futurism. It expands your own thought process of what’s possible and how to think about things. It opens your mind to the various possibilities of handling situations not only in the future but also in the present.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/KmhQvIwN">How to Change Your Workplace</a> – Adam Grant’s “Work Life” has been one of my all-time favorite podcasts and in this episode he delves into “Change” and how each one of us no matter where we are in the hierarchy can bring about meaningful, positive, long-lasting change and motivate people to embrace new ideas.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://cachelib.org/learnmore/">CacheLib</a> – Facebook’s web scale general purpose caching engine that powers multiple critical applications.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I did not succeed in Life because of Intelligence, I Succeeded because I have a long attention span</p><cite>Charlie Munger</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-11 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 24/Jun/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/06/24/friday-musings-24-jun-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Short stories I’m (re)reading I’ve been deeply inspired by some of these stories and it has stuck with me and has changed the way I [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-15 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-13 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Short stories I’m (re)reading</em></strong></h3>



<p>I’ve been deeply inspired by some of <a href="https://www.klib.in/short-life-stories/">these stories</a> and it has stuck with me and has changed the way I think and act.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=30vTc1SOt_w">Sensory Adaptation!</a> &nbsp;&#8211; Without this very strange phenomenon, you would be lost, overwhelmed, and completely unable to navigate the external world.</li></ul>



<h3><strong><em>Documentaries I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bFCOm1P_cQQ">The Brain that changes itself</a> – Our Brain is fantastic and continues to amaze researchers trying to unlock its secrets. You would’ve heard people say Change is hard and most people hate change, but if you look deep, your body and specifically your Brain is tuned efficiently adapt, handle and thrive with continuous changes.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><em> </em></strong><a href="https://neuralink.com/blog/monkey-mindpong/">Mind Pong!</a> – I’m so excited to see how tech like these will change our future and the things we’ll be able to accomplish. While a part of this brings hope, there’s fear on what this would do in the wrong hands.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Isn’t it a Paradox that we want a newer version of everything, but we fear to change our mind?</p><cite>Carmen Jacob</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-14 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 17/Jun/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/06/17/friday-musings-17-jun-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Places I visited I was fortunate this week to visit two historic temple sites in Tamilnadu, the Chidambaram Nataraja Temple and Vaithayanatha Swamy Temple in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-18 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-16 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Places I visited</em></strong></h3>



<p>I was fortunate this week to visit two historic temple sites in Tamilnadu, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nataraja_Temple,_Chidambaram">the Chidambaram Nataraja Temple</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vaitheeswaran_Koil">Vaithayanatha Swamy Temple</a> in VaitheeswaranKoil. It&#8217;s amazing to see the architectural marvels on these temples &#8211; thousands of carved stone pillars and replicas without a single imperfection. I&#8217;m not sure if one can achieve such a feat even with the latest scientific tools we have at our disposal now. Chidambaram Temple (more specifically the feet of Swamy Nataraja in the temple) is also believed to be the <a href="https://ramanisblog.in/2015/04/06/chidambaram-geomagnetic-centre-of-earth-universe-study/">center point of Earth&#8217;s Magnetic equator.</a> While recent estimations put the temple ~2 degrees off the magnetic equator, given the magnetic fields fluctuate, it may really have been accurate when the original temple was constructed.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Documentaries I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GYHu0ivfR_o">Ancient Aliens &#8211; Puzzling Pillars</a> – Temple pillars that can sing and reverberate. No existing technology can easily reproduce these ancient marvels at the scale it was done. One wonders, where&#8217;s all that lost knowledge from Ancient India. While I’ve still not visited Hampi, i was personally fortunate to experience the sounds from these stone pillars that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nellaiappar_Temple">Sri Nellayappar Temple in Tirunelveli</a>.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F-nNTGK0wFw">Unanswered &#8211; Mysteries from the Mahabharata | Christopher Charles Doyle | TEDxYouth@NMS</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6syj1PWMDLM">Did Ancient India have AI Robot Technology?</a></li></ul>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/05/23/openai-look-at-our-awesome-image-generator-google-hold-my-shiba-inu/">Google Imagen</a> &#8211; What is original / real / true? With tech like GPT-3, Imagen etc, answering questions like this, fact checking news articles, authenticating artwork will get increasingly difficult with expanding AI prowess.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Life is what happens to you while you’re busy making other plans.</p><cite>Allen Saunders</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-17 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 10/Jun/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/06/10/friday-musings-10-jun-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 07:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Podcasts I’m listening to Mind Reading 2.0: Why Conversations go wrong hosted by Shankar Vedantam (@HiddenBrain) where they talk about conversational styles and why understanding [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-21 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-19 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening to</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/why-conversations-go-wrong/">Mind Reading 2.0: Why Conversations go wrong</a> hosted by Shankar Vedantam (<a href="https://twitter.com/HiddenBrain">@HiddenBrain</a>) where they talk about conversational styles and why understanding them is important to be able to effectively communicate.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Articles I’m reading</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/top.html">The Top Idea in your mind</a> – Another one of those gems from Tim’s newsletter where Paul Graham writes about ambient thought.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=75d_29QWELk">Change your Life, one step at a time</a> : I’m a big fan of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/inanutshell">Kurzgesagt</a> videos and highly recommend it. This one came exactly when I was thinking of making some small changes in my lifestyle. I’ve been awe-inspired by the amount of research that goes behind making some of these videos. <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/sources-change/">Here&#8217;s</a> the supplementary info for this particular video.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><em> </em></strong><a href="https://makersacademy.medium.com/what-is-rubber-duck-debugging-d3028d70a707">Rubber Duck Debugging</a>. I never knew what I used occasionally as a Developer in the early days had a name and real psychology behind it!</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>One Man’s Terrorist is another’s man Freedom Fighter</p><cite>Anon</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-20 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Gardening teaches you about management!</title>
		<link>/2021/08/22/management/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the onset of the COVID-19 Pandemic, gardening has rapidly become a way to rejuvenate and is now a core family activity. Watching seeds germinate, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since the onset of the COVID-19 Pandemic, gardening has rapidly become a way to rejuvenate and is now a core family activity. Watching seeds germinate, flowers blossom, plants flourish(and sometimes dry out and die), I couldn’t help but draw parallels to management&nbsp;and the lessons we can learn from them.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote has-text-align-center has-small-font-size" style="font-style:normal;font-weight:500"><blockquote><p><mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" class="has-inline-color has-vivid-cyan-blue-color"><strong><em>The glory of gardening: hands in the dirt, head in the sun, heart with nature. To nurture a garden is to feed not just on the body, but the soul. &#8211; </em></strong></mark><strong><mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" class="has-inline-color has-vivid-cyan-blue-color"><em>Alfred Austin</em></mark></strong></p></blockquote></figure>



<div class="wp-block-cover" style="min-height:138px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim"></span><img loading="lazy" width="960" height="641" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-106" alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/sunsoil.jpeg" data-object-fit="cover" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/sunsoil.jpeg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/sunsoil-300x200.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/sunsoil-768x513.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container">
<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>Soil &amp; Sunlight &#8211; It all starts here</strong></p>
</div></div>



<p>Every plant needs a specific type of soil to flourish. Clay, Sandy, Silty, or Peaty.&nbsp;There are many&nbsp;combinations depending on what plants you’ve got. Likewise, sunlight is also an important growth factor. Some plants need full sunlight, others need partial shade, while some grow remarkably well indoors with minimal light. Using the wrong soil type or lighting is a sure shot way to fail.</p>



<p>Like soil and&nbsp;sunlight form the foundation for the growth of plants, the right work assignments determine your team&#8217;s success.&nbsp;<em>New project features</em><strong><em>&nbsp;</em></strong><em>vs</em>&nbsp;<em>fixing tech debt</em>&nbsp;<em>vs</em>&nbsp;<em>support</em>&nbsp;<em>vs</em>&nbsp;<em>building a product from scratch</em>, each needs a specific type of individual. Some are suited to platform work, some can learn new tech quickly and adapt to a fast-paced environment, some are very good at dealing with ambiguity, etc, so identify the right place for team members based on their skills, interests &amp; aspirations.</p>



<div class="wp-block-cover is-light" style="min-height:151px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim"></span><img loading="lazy" width="400" height="267" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-107" alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/waterfert.jpeg" data-object-fit="cover" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/waterfert.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/waterfert-300x200.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container">
<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong><mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#f3f2f2" class="has-inline-color">Water &amp; Fertilizer &#8211; Keep up the growth</mark></strong></p>
</div></div>



<p>Now that you have foundations out of the way, let&#8217;s talk about regular care.</p>



<p>Water and fertilizer are two very important&nbsp;needs for a splendid garden. Every plant in your garden may have&nbsp;a specific need. Some don’t need any fertilizer for months, while others need it every week. Same with water. Some plants have&nbsp;to be watered daily and others are drought resistant and can sustain for weeks. Root rot, yellowing leaves, stunted growth, fertilizer burns, etc are very common issues you&#8217;ll see in gardening support forums and the only way to fix them is to fix your watering and fertilizing schedules.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In management, this is like providing the right training, setting the right expectations, and following up on progress. Inadequate or incorrect training will create under-skilled members&nbsp;and frustrate the team.&nbsp;Lack of expectation setting and follow-up on progress will lead to suboptimal outcomes. Some team members do well with very minimal follow-up, whereas others will either need frequent follow-ups or someone to assist them continuously to ensure progress.&nbsp;<em>RCG&#8217;s, mid-level engineers, senior engineers, architects, managers</em>&nbsp;&#8211; each one has a different need and successful leaders should be mindful of these, spot opportunities, provide clarity for the team to flourish.</p>



<p>As a manager regularly ask yourself &#8211; Does your team have the right skills needed for the job? Do you micromanage a lot when you should let the team decide? Do you stay away from the action, only to pitch in when a crisis occurs?. Get your team&#8217;s feedback and adapt.</p>



<div class="wp-block-cover is-light" style="min-height:96px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim"></span><img loading="lazy" width="400" height="264" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-102" alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/climbers.jpeg" data-object-fit="cover" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/climbers.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/climbers-300x198.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container">
<p class="has-text-color has-large-font-size" style="color:#fefdfd"><strong>Climbers need stability &amp; support</strong></p>
</div></div>



<p>If you’ve grown flowering climbers (like Allamanda or morning glory) you may have noticed that beyond a certain height they can no longer grow without support. Strong Climbers sometimes use other branches in the same plant to continue growing, but even that has a limit.</p>



<p>The same is true for you and your team. Beyond a certain limit, they can no longer grow without leadership support. As a manager, always create the right support ecosystem both within and outside your teams. Find the right coaching / mentoring opportunities and share them. Have regular 1:1s and create an individual development plan which aligns with their aspirations.</p>



<div class="wp-block-cover" style="min-height:119px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim"></span><img loading="lazy" width="400" height="267" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-105" alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/seedsorstem.jpeg" data-object-fit="cover" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/seedsorstem.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/seedsorstem-300x200.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container">
<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>Seeds or stem cuttings &#8211; building next-gen</strong></p>
</div></div>



<p>While you may have picked the best seeds or the strongest cuttings for propagation, you may never see a 100% success rate. Anything between 50-70% is a respectable success rate and you’ll eventually get better. Time is another important factor to consider too. Some seeds germinate quickly while others will take more time, don’t judge too soon, and start taking action.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ll have similar observations during hiring as well. Someone fantastic during interviews&nbsp;can&nbsp;be inefficient at the job and an average person could&nbsp;be a rockstar. Give it time, observe progress at regular intervals, and course-correct accordingly. Don&#8217;t be too hard on yourself if you land a bad hire. Learn from it and move on. You&#8217;ll get better, eventually.</p>



<div class="wp-block-cover is-light" style="min-height:96px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim"></span><img loading="lazy" width="400" height="267" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-104" alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/repot.jpeg" data-object-fit="cover" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/repot.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/repot-300x200.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container">
<p class="has-white-color has-text-color has-large-font-size"><strong>Re-Potting &#8211; Moving on&#8230;</strong></p>
</div></div>



<p>All plants eventually outgrow their containers. For you to sustain their growth and keep them from dying, you’ll need to move them to a larger pot with more soil/nutrients.</p>



<p>Likewise, in management, you should always watch out for successful people on your teams who are now ready for expanded roles, scope, etc, and create opportunities for them to grow. Depending on your situation, you may need to move them to other teams or, in some rare cases, even encourage them to look outside of the company. Remember, this is both good for the individual and the team. You don’t want cracked pots or stunted plants!</p>



<div class="wp-block-cover" style="min-height:111px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim"></span><img loading="lazy" width="400" height="288" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-103" alt="" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/pruning.jpeg" data-object-fit="cover" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/pruning.jpeg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/pruning-300x216.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container">
<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>Pruning &#8211; It&#8217;s never easy</strong></p>
</div></div>



<p>Pruning boosts yields, improves aesthetics, reduces diseases &amp; prevents infestations. Every beautiful garden needs regular pruning. Don’t be afraid to prune &#8211; knowing when and how are important skills every gardener should learn.</p>



<p>Likewise, managers need&nbsp;to review their team structure periodically and make changes. You may have to remove misfits and underperformers, deliberately move out people who’ve been in your team for long to other teams, so they can grow (and your team can grow/adapt as well) or split teams into smaller units so they are more focused. Being a successful manager requires you to master these skills and know when the time is right to apply them.</p>



<pre class="wp-block-verse"><em><span class="has-inline-color has-vivid-cyan-blue-color">It’s important to realize that whether in plants or humans, growth is the same, and demands much of the same conditions and requirements. It’s hard work, takes a lot of effort and patience, but like a proud gardener admiring the beauty of their garden, seeing your team grow and succeed is both a rewarding and fulfilling part of being a manager.</span></em></pre>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Motive &#8211; Patrick Lencioni</title>
		<link>/2020/12/26/the-motive-patrick-lencioni/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 09:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Summaries]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2 Kinds of Leaders Reward centered They see the moving to leadership as a reward of what they’ve achieved so far and is a prize. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>2 Kinds of Leaders</h2>



<ul><li><strong><em>Reward centered</em></strong><ol><li>They see the moving to leadership as a reward of what they’ve achieved so far and is a prize.</li><li>Focus on the &#8220;glory&#8221;, &#8220;prestige&#8221;, &#8220;rewards&#8221; for achieving pinnacle of success</li><li>They usually pick and choose what they want to do as leader and do what is usually something they feel they are good at or have fun.</li></ol></li><li><strong><em>Responsibility centered</em></strong><ol type="i"><li>Look at this as a responsibility rather than reward.</li><li>Don’t shy away from doing what is required for someone at this job</li><li>The experience of being &#8216;<em>responsibility centered</em>&#8216; leader should be tough and challenging</li><li>Look at this from the perspective of the people they lead, rather than themselves.</li></ol></li></ul>



<ul><li>There&#8217;s no pure &#8220;Reward&#8221; / &#8220;Responsibility&#8221; focused Leader. People are usually in a spectrum. You need to ensure you are more aligned toward Responsibility centered.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Responsibility centered Leaders need to be aware of the <strong>Trap</strong> &#8211; when they are being responsibility centered leader, people tend to praise them and agree with them quite a lot and this can lead people to move down the path of Reward centered leadership.<ul><li>Have a strong inner circle who can challenge and keep them honest</li></ul></li></ul>



<h2><strong>5 Core responsibilities</strong> </h2>



<p>These are responsibilities that &#8220;<em>Reward centered</em>&#8221; Leaders usually ignore or don&#8217;t do well</p>



<ul><li><strong><em>Having difficult &amp; uncomfortable conversations</em></strong><ul><li>Addressing Bad behavior immediately and not tolerating regardless of how good the direct report is at their job</li><li>Don&#8217;t avoid these hard conversations</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><em>Managing subordinates</em></strong><ul><li>Individual coaching and guidance is necessary at all levels. This has got nothing to do with the person&#8217;s experience.</li><li><span class="has-inline-color has-luminous-vivid-orange-color"><em>If you feel you should be able to trust people to manage themselves, or justify not knowing what your direct reports are doing by justifying not being a micromanager, then your motive for leading is wrong.</em></span></li><li><strong><em>Micromanagement</em></strong> &#8212; <span class="has-inline-color has-luminous-vivid-orange-color">the only people who call management, micromanagement are the ones trying to avoid accountability</span>.</li><li><strong>As a leader, you need to</strong><ul><li>Know what they are working on</li><li>Know their progress</li><li>Give them the right feedback and coaching</li></ul></li><li>Lots of experience doesn&#8217;t mean people don&#8217;t have to be managed. It&#8217;s not sign of punishment or lack of trust. It&#8217;s giving them the benefit of direction and coaching.</li><li>Best of sportsmen pay people to coach them.</li><li>Stopping managing is a sign of neglect.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><em>Running great team meetings</em></strong><ul><li>Running boring meetings / avoiding them</li><li>Outcome based meetings</li><li>If you allow in-effective meetings to happens, this will percolate to entire org</li><li><strong><em>Bad Meetings == Bad decisions</em></strong></li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><em>Developing Leadership team</em></strong><ul><li>If you feel this is something touchy-feely and waste of time, then your motive for being a leader isn&#8217;t right.</li><li>Hiring != delegating to HR</li><li>It&#8217;s not just a annual meeting or gala for team building</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><em>Communicating constantly &amp; repeatedly</em></strong><ul><li>Research says it takes <strong>7 times</strong> for people to hear the same message before believe execs are serious about it.</li><li><strong>CEOs need to be Chief Reminding Officers</strong></li><li>You always need to over communicate.</li></ul></li></ul>



<h2>Quotes &amp; References</h2>



<ul><li><em>It’s about doing the job, not having the job.</em></li><li><em>CEO is not Chief Executive Officer , it is Chief </em><strong><em>Executing</em></strong><em> officer.</em></li><li><em>When deciding on picking up a certain role ask yourself</em><ul><li><strong><em>Why do you want to do the thing that __ does? (CEO/VP/Director etc)</em></strong></li><li><strong><em>Why do you still want to be _____ ? (CEO/VP/Director etc)</em></strong></li></ul></li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-embed aligncenter is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="UnConference Live Stream - &quot;Are You Leading for the Right Reasons?&quot;" width="819" height="461" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PdRcrNXZNjA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen title="UnConference Live Stream - "Are You Leading for the Right Reasons?""></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
