<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Infinite Possibilities</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/mySite/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Dare to Dream</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 16:23:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 12/Aug/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/08/12/friday-musings-12-aug-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 16:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’m reading. An Engineering team where everyone is a leader – A very well written piece with practical tips for managers and leaders on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-3 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-1 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Articles I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://blog.pragmaticengineer.com/a-team-where-everyone-is-a-leader/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">An Engineering team where everyone is a leader</a> – A very well written piece with practical tips for managers and leaders on how to build a team where each engineer is empowered to make decisions and leads from the front.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos I watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=biNMRQJXvfs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Why No One Can Agree What’s REALLY the Tallest Mountain</a> – Did you know that the longest mountain range in earth is under sea and the tallest peak isn&#8217;t necessarily the Everest? There&#8217;s never a time when I have come out of a video from this channel without learning something new and also wondering how some of the simplest things we assume from our schooling can actually be very complex.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Books I’m (re) Reading</em></strong></h3>



<p>Reread my notes from the book  <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3450744-nudge" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nudge</a> after listening to the recent episode of Hidden Brain on &#8220;<a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/you-2-0-how-to-see-yourself-clearly/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to see yourself clearly</a>&#8220;. The concept of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Choice_architecture" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">choice architecture</a> and its influence on people as described in Nudge made me think about comment from the podcast – “<em>We often make important decisions in our life and love for reasons we don&#8217;t even realize</em>”</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://levelup.gitconnected.com/why-firefox-deserves-its-sad-decline-1c44d9ba59c9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Firefox and its sad decline&#8230;</a> – I love Firefox, but this is an example what happens to a product when there&#8217;s mis-timing, lack of customer focus and market understanding issues coupled with bad decisions. It&#8217;s sad to see Firefox fall from over 34% browser market share in 2010 to less than 3.5% currently.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Every time someone does the right thing, the world becomes a better place to live in&#8230;</p><cite>Anon</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-2 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 05/Aug/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/08/05/friday-musings-05-aug-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 13:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=322</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’m reading. How to mend your broken pandemic brain – COVID-19 pandemic has truly hit the humankind in all possible areas including messing up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-6 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-4 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Articles I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/07/16/1028580/pandemic-mental-health-new-normal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to mend your broken pandemic brain</a> – COVID-19 pandemic has truly hit the humankind in all possible areas including messing up our brains. As the world slowly starts its recovery journey, this article talks about some of the impacts to our brain and how we can help fix it faster.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Movies I watched</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt9263550/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rocketry &#8211; The Nambi Effect</a> – (IMDb &#8211; 9.1) &#8211; After many months, this was a movie that shook me. Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/ActorMadhavan" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">R.Madhavan</a> for making this and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nambi_Narayanan" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dr. Nambi</a> an unsung hero who&#8217;s love for this country and passion for science has no parallels. What intrigued me when I watched this movie, is the impact media (news/television/social media etc.) has in creating a viral perception (right /wrong) about a person and how we as consumers embrace that without question and judge people. In an era of AI taking over content creation and propagation, it&#8217;s very important that each one of us have some moral and factual compass before coming to a judgement on piece of info we see out there.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/you-2-0-befriending-your-inner-voice/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">You 2.0 &#8211; Befriending your inner voice</a> – What we say to ourselves, and our inner voice is a big contributor to how we think, act, react and transform. This podcast covers the effect of this chatter, and how to keep our negative emotions from transforming to chatter and harness its power in a constructive way.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp; </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://github.com/jorgef/engineeringladders" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Engineering Ladders</a> – This is a wonderful resource for Managers that’ll help in having meaningful career conversations around expectations at each level for both Engineering and management tracks. This is not intended to be used as a checklist for promotions, rather a guidance for career conversations</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>People rarely succeed unless they have fun in what they are doing</p><cite>Dale Carnegie</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-5 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 29/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/30/friday-musings-29-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 11:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=315</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’m reading. Ask HN: I&#8217;m in a rut. How did you get out of yours? – This active thread on HackerNews has lot of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-9 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-7 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Articles I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32226910">Ask HN: I&#8217;m in a rut. How did you get out of yours?</a> – This active thread on HackerNews has lot of tips and discussions on how to handle and recover from Burnout and languishing. What intrigued me was, how a simple question when asked in a powerful forum could lead to tons of learning. Never be afraid to ask questions!</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p>As someone who personally struggles with initiating the first conversation, I found &nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F4Zu5ZZAG7I">7 Ways to Make a Conversation with Anyone</a> very insightful and practical. It’s a beautiful TEDx talk that you’ll appreciate if you are working to get better at connecting and talking to someone.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://freakonomics.com/podcast/should-you-try-to-be-less-angry/">Should You Try to Be Less Angry?</a> – Another one from my favorite podcasts – “No Stupid Questions” where Angela and Stephen discuss about Anger and it effects. While it’s not always good to keep the pot boiling, Anger as evolutionary measure does come in handy in situations and it is important we learn more about how to tackle our emotions and understand its effects.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://refactoring.fm/p/the-power-of-inversion-">Power of Inversion</a> – &#8220;<em>Avoiding stupidity is easier than seeking brilliance</em>&#8220;. This post explores some common applications of the Inversion mental model in engineering and how we can use it to make things better.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Almost any technology that has the power to save a billion lives, always starts with something that could kill a million</p><cite>Anon</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-8 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Manager Surprises</title>
		<link>/2022/07/23/new-manager-surprises/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 09:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently, I spoke to a group of new managers (mostly) and people who&#8217;ve transitioned from a Product/Program Management role about surprises that new people managers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Recently, I spoke to a group of new managers (mostly) and people who&#8217;ve transitioned from a Product/Program Management role about surprises that new people managers encounter. This talk was a drill down (albeit with a slight improvisation) on the research conducted by <a href="https://hbr.org/search?term=michael%20e.%20porter">Michael E. Porter,</a><a href="https://hbr.org/search?term=jay%20w.%20lorsch">Jay W. Lorsch,</a> and <a href="https://hbr.org/search?term=nitin%20nohria">Nitin Nohria</a> which was outlined in their 2004 HBR article titled <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hbr.org/2004/10/seven-surprises-for-new-ceos" target="_blank"><em>Seven Surprises for New CEOs </em></a>. While the article dates back to 2004, the findings remain relevant even today.</p>



<p>While the original content was written with CEOs in mind, I&#8217;ve adapted that to managers at all levels given the audience of this networking session.</p>



<hr class="flaired">


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1-1024x663.png" alt="" class="wp-image-280" width="628" height="406" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1-1024x663.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1-300x194.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1-768x497.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mgmt-art-sci-1.png 1307w" sizes="(max-width: 628px) 100vw, 628px" /></figure></div>


<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong><em>Management</em></strong> is both  <strong><em>Art</em></strong> and <strong><em>Science</em></strong>. It is <em>science</em> because there&#8217;s systemic study material, repeatable processes, and causality that can be learnt. It&#8217;s an Art because management requires a considerable amount of skill, practice, creativity and Individual application &#8211; what works for one may not work for another person. It&#8217;s therefore imperative to understand what one can expect as they embark on their management journey and chart a course for success. </p>



<p>Let&#8217;s start with what new managers may find surprising as they embark on their management journey</p>



<br style="clear:left"><hr class="flaired">



<h3>You <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">can&#8217;t</mark> do everything</h3>



<p>As you enter management, you have to get comfortable with the feeling that you can&#8217;t be directly involved with everything that&#8217;s happening in your project / organization, yet you are fully accountable for outcomes &amp; results. This is in stark contrast to back when you were an individual contributor and now your time will be needed in more places than you can imagine.</p>



<p>To avoid/overcome problems with this surprise, you have to learn to</p>



<ol><li>Effectively <a href="#delegation">Delegate</a> to your direct reports and trust them</li><li>Manage your <a href="#timemanagement">time efficiently</a></li></ol>



<h3>You <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">can&#8217;t</mark> always tell people what to do</h3>



<p>You cannot micromanage every decision by telling people how to do things. Like Steve jobs said &#8220;<code><em>It doesn't make sense to hire smart people and then tell them what to to , We hire smart people so they can tell us what to do</em></code><strong><em>.</em>”</strong> We should enable people by providing the right amount of clarity on the needs and expectations around outcomes/ results and provide autonomy to execute.</p>



<p>Practice the following and you&#8217;ll steer clear and learn more</p>



<ul><li>Provide Clarity<ul><li>Set Vision &amp; Standards </li><li>Define operating principles (review cadence, stakeholder communication, cost etc)</li><li>Learn from mistakes (remember that we all learn from our mistakes, so create and embrace a culture where people can freely talk about failures and learnings from them)</li></ul></li><li>Avoid Decision Bottlenecks<ul><li>Share power and make people part of the decision making process. This can hugely improve trust.</li><li>Encourage the culture of calculated risk taking.</li><li>Learn and make use of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.guru99.com/decision-making-tools.html" target="_blank">Decision making tools</a>.</li></ul></li></ul>



<h3>You <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">won&#8217;t</mark> always know what&#8217;s going on</h3>



<p>As a manager, you&#8217;ll have a lot of things going on around you (meetings, stakeholder management, planning, people issues, budgeting, hiring, performance management and tons more). Amidst all of that, it&#8217;s very difficult to keep track of every aspect of what&#8217;s happening. People won&#8217;t immediately be willing to give you the bad news, so by the time it gets to you, it may be late or have some glossy touches added.</p>



<p>But to manage effectively, you need to stay on top of things and be in the loop. Here are some thoughts on what can help you get there.</p>



<ul><li>Identify ways to collect as much information as possible about what&#8217;s happening in the team from different sources.<ul><li>Practice <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Management_by_wandering_around" target="_blank">Management by walking around (MBWA)</a></li><li>Another alternate is <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gemba#:~:text=The%20Gemba%20Walk%20is%20an,results%20or%20make%20superficial%20comments." target="_blank">Gemba walk</a>, popularized by Toyota, where you walk to the place where the action happens, ask questions and learn.</li><li>Have skip level 1:1s and team meetings.</li></ul></li><li>Build strong partnerships with all your stakeholders<ul><li>Talk to your peers, customers, cross functional leaders, HR partners etc. This will give you a rounded perspective of what&#8217;s happening.</li></ul></li></ul>



<h3>You are always being <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">watched</mark>!</h3>



<p>I don&#8217;t&#8217; say this as something to be scared about, but as a manager/leader of the organization, you are always sending a message. The way you speak (or don’t speak!), your body language, choice of words, way to write, everything starts to matter now. People will try to read between lines and there are chances you can be misinterpreted.</p>



<p>To avoid potential issues because of this, try to</p>



<ul><li>Lead by example. Role model the behavior you would like to see in your team members. Your actions will soon be replicated in your team, so use it to your advantage.</li><li>Communicate clearly and ask for clarifications. Don&#8217;t assume people understood what you said.</li><li>Improve your self-awareness and Emotional Quotient</li><li>This is a continuous learning process, so you will have Blind spots. Get an <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://actionbuddy.io/blog/accountability-partner#:~:text=An%20accountability%20partner%20is%20someone,to%20stick%20to%20their%20commitments." target="_blank">accountability partner</a> who can help provide feedback.</li></ul>



<h3>Organizational Politics is <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">real</mark>!</h3>



<p>Not all politics is bad. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://opentext.wsu.edu/organizational-behavior/chapter/13-4-organizational-politics/" target="_blank">Organizational politics</a> is real and how well you deal with it will also define your success trajectory. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hbr.org/2017/04/the-4-types-of-organizational-politics" target="_blank">Studies show</a> that individuals with political skills tend to have a greater impact on organizational outcomes. Understanding and navigating organizational politics and improving your influencing authority will provide better outcomes for your teams.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-301" width="333" height="303" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/image.png 329w, /wp-content/uploads/2022/07/image-300x273.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 333px) 100vw, 333px" /><figcaption>Credits: Mindtools &#8211; <a href="https://www.mindtools.com/pages/article/newPPM_07.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stakeholder Analysis</a></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Here are some thoughts about how to handle this</p>



<ul><li>Be Politically Savvy. What this means is that you are aware of what’s going on around you, you’re paying attention to the dynamics, paying attention to who has power and influence, and what the culture of your organization is, and you are positioning yourself successfully with all that information.</li><li>Build and leverage your network.</li><li>Understand your stakeholders and map them. <em>Power/interest grid for stakeholder prioritization</em> on the left can be one useful technique.</li></ul>



<div style="clear:right"></div>



<h3>You are still only <mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0);color:#cf0808" class="has-inline-color">Human</mark>!</h3>



<p>You must remember that your position as a manager/leader does not automatically make you better or more capable. Like everyone else, you will learn from experience and the many mistakes that&#8217;ll provide important lessons along the way. However, as a manager, you have more accountability and responsibility, and how you role model your behaviors will be replicated.</p>



<p>It is essential to keep the following things in mind as you embark on your management/leadership journey.</p>



<ul><li>Your Work/Life balance is extremely important and how you manage it will be emulated by your team. Remember your mood will affect your team&#8217;s mood as well.<ul><li>A friend once gave me this priority list that I strive to follow &#8211; Health -> Family -> Relationships -> Work</li></ul></li><li>Being vulnerable and asking for help will improve trust with your teams and you&#8217;ll achieve more together.</li><li>Be Thankful, stay humble and praise generously.</li><li>Get a mentor/coach who can help you along the way and share their learnings.</li></ul>



<br><hr class="flaired">



<h4>Appendix</h4>



<ul id="delegation"><li><strong><em>Delegation</em></strong> is the assignment of authority to another person (normally from a manager to a subordinate) to carry out specific activities. It is the process of distributing and entrusting work to another person, and therefore one of the core concepts of management leadership. The process involves managers deciding which work they should do themselves and which work should be delegated to others for completion.[1] From a managerial standpoint, delegation involves shifting project responsibility to team members, giving them the opportunity to finalize the work product effectively, with minimal intervention. The opposite of effective delegation is micromanagement, where a manager provides too much input, direction, and review of delegated work. Delegation empowers a subordinate to make decisions. It is a shifting of decision-making authority as well as responsibility for the results from one organisational level to another lower one. However, a certain level of accountability for the outcome of the work does remain with the person who delegated the work to begin with.<ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://online.hbs.edu/blog/post/how-to-delegate-effectively" target="_blank">How to Delegate Effectively</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/shreyas/status/1401615513998950401" target="_blank">Radical Delegation by Shreyas Doshi</a></li></ul></li></ul>



<ul id="timemanagement"><li><strong><em>Time Management</em></strong><ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://todoist.com/productivity-methods/eisenhower-matrix" target="_blank">Eisenhower Matrix</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.business2community.com/strategy/6-time-management-techniques-to-help-you-get-everything-done-02166826" target="_blank">Other Techniques</a></li></ul></li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 22/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/22/friday-musings-22-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 05:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’m reading. How can I become a Director? &#160;– A very well written piece by Guru Bhat on what it takes to become a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-12 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-10 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Articles I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-can-i-become-director-guru-bhat/">How can I become a Director? </a>&nbsp;– A very well written piece by Guru Bhat on what it takes to become a director. Eloquent as always, Guru hits the bulls eye on some key attributes that everyone should aspire to attain if they are on a quest for this title. I’ve been fortunate to learn by experience how “Bias for Action” can be a key differentiator in creating value for our stakeholders.</p>



<h3><strong><em>What worries me!</em></strong></h3>



<p>It’s hard to miss the series of natural calamities rocking the already pandemic struck world right now. From the <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2022/07/19/google_oracle_cloud/?mc_cid=1674b3c928&amp;mc_eid=2b8cf1fb98">extreme heat waves in UK &amp; Europe</a> to <a href="https://www.thenationalnews.com/world/asia/2022/07/21/indias-monsoon-havoc-a-result-of-climate-change-experts-say/">Cloud bursts and Flash floods in India</a>, It’s time each one of us do our part to slow down climate change. <a href="https://medium.com/@cinthia.espino/why-is-0-5-c-so-important-3961b9989387">Read this</a> if you want to know what a 0.5° Celsius change could mean to earth and <a href="https://coastal.climatecentral.org/map/10/72.9068/18.9721/?theme=sea_level_rise&amp;map_type=year&amp;basemap=roadmap&amp;contiguous=true&amp;elevation_model=best_available&amp;forecast_year=2040&amp;pathway=ssp3rcp70&amp;percentile=p50&amp;refresh=true&amp;return_level=return_level_0&amp;rl_model=gtsr&amp;slr_model=ipcc_2021_med">see these projections</a> of cities that would be under water if the sea-levels continues to rise.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://tim.blog/2022/06/28/edward-o-thorp-2/">Master Investor Ed Thorp on How to think for yourself and many more topics</a> – This is a long format podcast but there&#8217;s some invaluable takeaways from Ed&#8217;s experience. I&#8217;m a big fan of the Tim&#8217;s questions to his guests and the insights that he gleans from them. What particularly excited me in this podcast was how Ed was leveraging the power of compounding in anything he does, be it investing, loosing weight, forming habits, learning new things etc. Really loved the concept of &#8220;scrap time&#8221; and hope to incorporate in my life as well.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://wasp-lang.dev/blog/2022/06/24/ML-code-gen-vs-coding-by-hand-future">ML Codegen Vs Coding by Hand</a> – In the previous musings I shared about auto code-gen and it got me intrigued into aspects that are debatable and why we should tread with care. This post explores some of this nuance and has a good further reading on other thoughts on the same topic as well</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>If you really think that the environment is less important than the economy, try holding your breath while you count your money</p><cite>Guy McPherson</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-11 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 15/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/15/friday-musings-15-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Article I’m reading. Injections that edit Genes to stop diseases! – I’m filled with both hope and fear when I read articles like this. While [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-15 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-13 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Article I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/07/12/1055773/crispr-gene-editing-cholesterol/">Injections that edit Genes to stop diseases!</a> – I’m filled with both hope and fear when I read articles like this. While this has the power to save millions of people, what stops someone from using the same tech for nefarious purposes.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Places I’ve travelled.</em></strong></h3>



<p>I was in Bangalore this week meeting my colleagues in-person in office and wow, what a week it was. While there’s comfort &amp; some flexibility in working from home, nothing can beat the in-person collaboration and getting things done quickly. For me, Video calls somehow reduce the personal &amp; emotional side of the conversation. Looking forward to many more such visits and catching up with my people!</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/why-youre-smarter-than-you-think/">Why you&#8217;re smarter than you think!</a> – From the Hidden brain show notes – “<em>From the time we are schoolchildren, we are ranked and sorted based on how smart we are. But what if our assumptions about intelligence limit our potential? This week, psychologist Scott Barry Kaufman proposes a more expansive notion of what it means to be “smart</em>&#8220;.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><em> </em></strong><a href="https://simonwillison.net/2022/Jul/9/gpt-3-explain-code/">Can GPT-3 explain how code works?</a> – I was amazed by the extent to which models like GPT-3 &amp; OpenAI Codex are getting increasingly efficient at writing code. Makes me wonder when we’d land in a situation where we no longer hire programmers</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>You wouldn&#8217;t worry so much about what others think of you if you realized how seldom they do</p><cite>Elenaor Roosevelt</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-14 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 08/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/08/friday-musings-08-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 04:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Article I’m reading. How to work with someone you can’t stand – “Like it or not, your job and reputation can rely on an ability [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div class="wp-container-18 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-16 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<h3><strong><em>Article I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90596343/how-to-work-with-someone-you-cant-stand">How to work with someone you can’t stand</a> –</strong>  “<em>Like it or not, your job and reputation can rely on an ability to get along with others.”</em> Valdes-Dapena says there are steps you can take to make the situation more bearable.”</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2A7mblg5UKc">Trying to Land a Plane (to Prove a Point)</a> &nbsp;</strong>&#8211; <em>I’ve always been intrigued by Dunning-Krueger effect &amp; Imposter Syndrome and how it pretty much manifests in everybody. Personally I’m starting to get comfortable saying “I Don’t Know” and “I need help” more often these days.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://freakonomics.com/podcast/how-simple-is-too-simple/"><strong>How simple is too simple</strong></a> –<em> In this episode of “No Stupid Questions”, Angela Duckworth and Stephen Dubner discuss the obsession humans have with magic bullet solutions and why there are no simple answers.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.morling.dev/blog/whats-in-a-good-error-message/">What&#8217;s in a good Error Message</a>? </strong>– <em>Extremely important for all engineering devs and leads reviewing code. Both the article and the discussion/comments following it has several extremely using nuggets we should think about.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Quote I’m thinking about!</em></strong> </h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“What is Common Sense, isn’t Common Practice” – Stephen Covey</p></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-17 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 01/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/01/friday-musings-01-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Books I’m (re)reading. I’ve picked up “Radical Candor” by Kim Scott again. IMO, it’s one of the must reads for anyone picking up Management for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-21 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-19 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Books I’m (re)reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p>I’ve picked up <a href="https://www.radicalcandor.com/the-book/">“Radical Candor” by Kim Scott</a> again. IMO, it’s one of the must reads for anyone picking up Management for their career. It shows managers how to be successful while retaining their humanity, finding meaning in their job, and creating an environment where people both love their work and their colleagues</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEENEFaVUzU">The Last Human! &#8211; A Glimpse into&nbsp; the Far Future</a> &nbsp;&#8211; I’ve always been mesmerized by Futurism. It expands your own thought process of what’s possible and how to think about things. It opens your mind to the various possibilities of handling situations not only in the future but also in the present.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/KmhQvIwN">How to Change Your Workplace</a> – Adam Grant’s “Work Life” has been one of my all-time favorite podcasts and in this episode he delves into “Change” and how each one of us no matter where we are in the hierarchy can bring about meaningful, positive, long-lasting change and motivate people to embrace new ideas.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://cachelib.org/learnmore/">CacheLib</a> – Facebook’s web scale general purpose caching engine that powers multiple critical applications.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I did not succeed in Life because of Intelligence, I Succeeded because I have a long attention span</p><cite>Charlie Munger</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-20 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 24/Jun/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/06/24/friday-musings-24-jun-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Short stories I’m (re)reading I’ve been deeply inspired by some of these stories and it has stuck with me and has changed the way I [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-24 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-22 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Short stories I’m (re)reading</em></strong></h3>



<p>I’ve been deeply inspired by some of <a href="https://www.klib.in/short-life-stories/">these stories</a> and it has stuck with me and has changed the way I think and act.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=30vTc1SOt_w">Sensory Adaptation!</a> &nbsp;&#8211; Without this very strange phenomenon, you would be lost, overwhelmed, and completely unable to navigate the external world.</li></ul>



<h3><strong><em>Documentaries I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bFCOm1P_cQQ">The Brain that changes itself</a> – Our Brain is fantastic and continues to amaze researchers trying to unlock its secrets. You would’ve heard people say Change is hard and most people hate change, but if you look deep, your body and specifically your Brain is tuned efficiently adapt, handle and thrive with continuous changes.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><em> </em></strong><a href="https://neuralink.com/blog/monkey-mindpong/">Mind Pong!</a> – I’m so excited to see how tech like these will change our future and the things we’ll be able to accomplish. While a part of this brings hope, there’s fear on what this would do in the wrong hands.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Isn’t it a Paradox that we want a newer version of everything, but we fear to change our mind?</p><cite>Carmen Jacob</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-23 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 17/Jun/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/06/17/friday-musings-17-jun-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Places I visited I was fortunate this week to visit two historic temple sites in Tamilnadu, the Chidambaram Nataraja Temple and Vaithayanatha Swamy Temple in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-27 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-25 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Places I visited</em></strong></h3>



<p>I was fortunate this week to visit two historic temple sites in Tamilnadu, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nataraja_Temple,_Chidambaram">the Chidambaram Nataraja Temple</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vaitheeswaran_Koil">Vaithayanatha Swamy Temple</a> in VaitheeswaranKoil. It&#8217;s amazing to see the architectural marvels on these temples &#8211; thousands of carved stone pillars and replicas without a single imperfection. I&#8217;m not sure if one can achieve such a feat even with the latest scientific tools we have at our disposal now. Chidambaram Temple (more specifically the feet of Swamy Nataraja in the temple) is also believed to be the <a href="https://ramanisblog.in/2015/04/06/chidambaram-geomagnetic-centre-of-earth-universe-study/">center point of Earth&#8217;s Magnetic equator.</a> While recent estimations put the temple ~2 degrees off the magnetic equator, given the magnetic fields fluctuate, it may really have been accurate when the original temple was constructed.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Documentaries I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GYHu0ivfR_o">Ancient Aliens &#8211; Puzzling Pillars</a> – Temple pillars that can sing and reverberate. No existing technology can easily reproduce these ancient marvels at the scale it was done. One wonders, where&#8217;s all that lost knowledge from Ancient India. While I’ve still not visited Hampi, i was personally fortunate to experience the sounds from these stone pillars that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nellaiappar_Temple">Sri Nellayappar Temple in Tirunelveli</a>.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F-nNTGK0wFw">Unanswered &#8211; Mysteries from the Mahabharata | Christopher Charles Doyle | TEDxYouth@NMS</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6syj1PWMDLM">Did Ancient India have AI Robot Technology?</a></li></ul>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/05/23/openai-look-at-our-awesome-image-generator-google-hold-my-shiba-inu/">Google Imagen</a> &#8211; What is original / real / true? With tech like GPT-3, Imagen etc, answering questions like this, fact checking news articles, authenticating artwork will get increasingly difficult with expanding AI prowess.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Life is what happens to you while you’re busy making other plans.</p><cite>Allen Saunders</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-26 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
