<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Collections &#8211; Infinite Possibilities</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/mySite/category/collections/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Dare to Dream</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 13:00:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Favorite Quotes</title>
		<link>/2022/09/10/favorite-quotes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 11:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Collections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you set your goals ridiculously high and it&#8217;s a failure, you will fail above everyone else&#8217;s success. James Cameron Never argue with stupid people, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-style-default has-small-font-size" style="font-style:normal;font-weight:300"><p>If you set your goals ridiculously high and it&#8217;s a failure, you will fail above everyone else&#8217;s success.</p><p>James Cameron</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Never argue with stupid people, they will drag you down to their level and beat you with experience.</p><p>Mark Twain (apocryphal)</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Everything that irritates us about others can lead us to an understanding of ourselves</p><p>Carl Jung</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Every time someone does the right thing, the world becomes a better place to live in…</p><p>Anon</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>People rarely succeed unless they have fun in what they are doing</p><p>Dale Carnegie</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Almost any technology that has the power to save a billion lives, always starts with something that could kill a million</p><p>Anon</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>If you really think that the environment is less important than the economy, try holding your breath while you count your money</p><p>Guy McPherson</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>You wouldn&#8217;t worry so much about what others think of you if you realized how seldom they do</p><p>Elenaor Roosevelt</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“What is Common Sense, isn’t Common Practice” – Stephen Covey</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I did not succeed in Life because of Intelligence, I Succeeded because I have a long attention span</p><p>Charlie Munger</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Isn’t it a Paradox that we want a newer version of everything, but we fear to change our mind?</p><p>Carmen Jacob</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Life is what happens to you while you’re busy making other plans.</p><p>Allen Saunders</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>One Man’s Terrorist is another’s man Freedom Fighter</p><p>Anon</p></blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-dots"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Documentaries</title>
		<link>/2022/09/10/documentaries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 11:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Collections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The extraordinary Genius of Albert Einstein ” (Youtube)- reflecting on the principle of relativity in terms of social relations and individual identities or thought processes, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="height:20px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<ul><li>&#8220;<em>The extraordinary Genius of Albert Einstein</em> ” (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C8Zkd9VYdp4" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Youtube</a>)- reflecting on the principle of relativity in terms of social relations and individual identities or thought processes, asking the question &#8211; how was Einstein able to make his breakthrough?</li><li>&#8221; <em>Can we all become Geniuses</em> ” (<a href="https://www.discoveryplus.in/videos/morgan-freemans-through-the-wormhole/can-we-all-become-geniuses?seasonId=7&amp;type=EPISODE" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Discovery+)</a> &#8211; From the episode of &#8220;Through the Wormhole&#8221; narrated by Morgan Freeman &#8211; Genius lies somewhere in the human mind, bringing mathematical insight, sparking artistic inspiration and enabling some to see what most cannot. Might we augment our biology with technology to unlock the genius inside us all?</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bFCOm1P_cQQ" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">The Brain that changes itself</a> – Our Brain is fantastic and continues to amaze researchers trying to unlock its secrets. You would’ve heard people say Change is hard and most people hate change, but if you look deep, your body and specifically your Brain is tuned efficiently adapt, handle and thrive with continuous changes.</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GYHu0ivfR_o" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Ancient Aliens &#8211; Puzzling Pillars</a> – Temple pillars that can sing and reverberate. No existing technology can easily reproduce these ancient marvels at the scale it was done. One wonders, where&#8217;s all that lost knowledge from Ancient India. While I’ve still not visited Hampi, i was personally fortunate to experience the sounds from these stone pillars that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nellaiappar_Temple" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Sri Nellayappar Temple in Tirunelveli</a>.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tech Readings</title>
		<link>/2022/09/10/tech-readings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 11:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Collections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taking it light and doing a small tech history lesson, Where GREP Came From &#8211; Computerphile – Computerphile was recommended to me by Hari and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="height:20px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<ul><li>Taking it light and doing a small tech history lesson, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NTfOnGZUZDk" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Where GREP Came From &#8211; Computerphile</a> – Computerphile was recommended to me by <strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hariprasadkulkarni/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Hari</a></strong> and I found some of their content very informative with some interesting speakers on the lineup.</li><li><a href="https://siliconangle.com/2022/08/31/meta-ai-researchers-develop-ways-read-speech-peoples-brains/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Meta &#8211; AI, Read speech from Brain</a> – I’ve always been fascinated with the human brain and wondered if we’d ever fully understand and decode its inner workings. Here’s an interested read where Meta’s FAIR lab has been able to decode speech from non-invasive recordings of brain activity! Mind reading slowly becoming real.</li><li><strong>__</strong><a href="https://facebook.github.io/zstd/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">ZStandard</a>&nbsp;–&nbsp;Thanks&nbsp; <strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/subramaniajeeva/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Jeeva</a></strong> &nbsp;for sharing this one. ZStandard is a fast compression algorithm, providing high compression ratios. It also offers a special mode for small data, called dictionary compression. The reference library offers a very wide range of speed / compression trade-off, and is backed by an extremely fast decoder</li><li><a href="https://levelup.gitconnected.com/why-firefox-deserves-its-sad-decline-1c44d9ba59c9" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Firefox and its sad decline…</a> – I love Firefox, but this is an example what happens to a product when there&#8217;s mis-timing, lack of customer focus and market understanding issues coupled with bad decisions. It&#8217;s sad to see Firefox fall from over 34% browser market share in 2010 to less than 3.5% currently.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/jorgef/engineeringladders" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Engineering Ladders</a> – This is a wonderful resource for Managers that’ll help in having meaningful career conversations around expectations at each level for both Engineering and management tracks. This is not intended to be used as a checklist for promotions, rather a guidance for career conversations</li><li><a href="https://refactoring.fm/p/the-power-of-inversion-" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Power of Inversion</a> – &#8221; <em>Avoiding stupidity is easier than seeking brilliance</em> &#8220;. This post explores some common applications of the Inversion mental model in engineering and how we can use it to make things better.</li><li><a href="https://wasp-lang.dev/blog/2022/06/24/ML-code-gen-vs-coding-by-hand-future" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">ML Codegen Vs Coding by Hand</a> – In the previous musings I shared about auto code-gen and it got me intrigued into aspects that are debatable and why we should tread with care. This post explores some of this nuance and has a good further reading on other thoughts on the same topic as well</li><li><strong>__</strong><a href="https://simonwillison.net/2022/Jul/9/gpt-3-explain-code/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Can GPT-3 explain how code works?</a> – I was amazed by the extent to which models like GPT-3 &amp; OpenAI Codex are getting increasingly efficient at writing code. Makes me wonder when we’d land in a situation where we no longer hire programmers</li><li>**<a href="https://www.morling.dev/blog/whats-in-a-good-error-message/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">What&#8217;s in a good Error Message</a>? **– <em>Extremely important for all engineering devs and leads reviewing code. Both the article and the discussion/comments following it has several extremely using nuggets we should think about.</em></li><li><a href="https://cachelib.org/learnmore/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">CacheLib</a> – Facebook’s web scale general purpose caching engine that powers multiple critical applications.</li><li><strong>__</strong><a href="https://neuralink.com/blog/monkey-mindpong/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Mind Pong!</a> – I’m so excited to see how tech like these will change our future and the things we’ll be able to accomplish. While a part of this brings hope, there’s fear on what this would do in the wrong hands.</li><li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/05/23/openai-look-at-our-awesome-image-generator-google-hold-my-shiba-inu/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Google Imagen</a> &#8211; What is original / real / true? With tech like GPT-3, Imagen etc, answering questions like this, fact checking news articles, authenticating artwork will get increasingly difficult with expanding AI prowess.</li><li><strong>__</strong><a href="https://makersacademy.medium.com/what-is-rubber-duck-debugging-d3028d70a707" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Rubber Duck Debugging</a>. I never knew what I used occasionally as a Developer in the early days had a name and real psychology behind it!</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Podcasts Episodes</title>
		<link>/2022/09/10/podcasts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 11:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Collections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a list of Podcast episodes i&#8217;ve found worth sharing. Authenticity is a double-edged sword – Another gem from Adam Grant where he talks about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="height:26px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h6>Here&#8217;s a list of Podcast episodes i&#8217;ve found worth sharing.</h6>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/worklife_with_adam_grant_authenticity_is_a_double_edged_sword" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Authenticity is a double-edged sword</a> – Another gem from Adam Grant where he talks about what effective authenticity looks like and how we can learn to strike the right balance.</li><li><a href="https://hubermanlab.com/sleep-toolkit-tools-for-optimizing-sleep-and-sleep-wake-timing/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Sleep Toolkit: Tools For Optimizing Sleep &amp; Sleep-Wake Timing</a>&nbsp;&#8211;&nbsp;Dr. Huberman provides practical tips to improve and optimize sleep patterns. I&#8217;ve personally incorporated some of this (morning sunlight exposure, core body temperature rise, early dinner)&nbsp; in my daily routine and can definitely see improvements in waking up energy, sleep quality etc.</li><li><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/you-2-0-befriending-your-inner-voice/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">You 2.0 &#8211; Befriending your inner voice</a> – What we say to ourselves, and our inner voice is a big contributor to how we think, act, react and transform. This podcast covers the effect of this chatter, and how to keep our negative emotions from transforming to chatter and harness its power in a constructive way.</li><li><a href="https://freakonomics.com/podcast/should-you-try-to-be-less-angry/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Should You Try to Be Less Angry?</a> – Another one from my favorite podcasts – “No Stupid Questions” where Angela and Stephen discuss about Anger and it effects. While it’s not always good to keep the pot boiling, Anger as evolutionary measure does come in handy in situations and it is important we learn more about how to tackle our emotions and understand its effects.</li><li><a href="https://tim.blog/2022/06/28/edward-o-thorp-2/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Master Investor Ed Thorp on How to think for yourself and many more topics</a> – This is a long format podcast but there&#8217;s some invaluable takeaways from Ed&#8217;s experience. I&#8217;m a big fan of the Tim&#8217;s questions to his guests and the insights that he gleans from them. What particularly excited me in this podcast was how Ed was leveraging the power of compounding in anything he does, be it investing, loosing weight, forming habits, learning new things etc. Really loved the concept of &#8220;scrap time&#8221; and hope to incorporate in my life as well.</li><li><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/why-youre-smarter-than-you-think/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Why you&#8217;re smarter than you think!</a> – From the Hidden brain show notes – “ <em>From the time we are schoolchildren, we are ranked and sorted based on how smart we are. But what if our assumptions about intelligence limit our potential? This week, psychologist Scott Barry Kaufman proposes a more expansive notion of what it means to be “smart</em> &#8220;.</li><li><a href="https://freakonomics.com/podcast/how-simple-is-too-simple/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><strong>How simple is too simple</strong></a> – <em>In this episode of “No Stupid Questions”, Angela Duckworth and Stephen Dubner discuss the obsession humans have with magic bullet solutions and why there are no simple answers.</em></li><li><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/KmhQvIwN" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">How to Change Your Workplace</a> – Adam Grant’s “Work Life” has been one of my all-time favorite podcasts and in this episode he delves into “Change” and how each one of us no matter where we are in the hierarchy can bring about meaningful, positive, long-lasting change and motivate people to embrace new ideas.</li><li><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/why-conversations-go-wrong/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Mind Reading 2.0: Why Conversations go wrong</a> hosted by Shankar Vedantam (<a href="https://twitter.com/HiddenBrain" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">@HiddenBrain</a>) where they talk about conversational styles and why understanding them is important to be able to effectively communicate.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Videos</title>
		<link>/2022/09/10/videos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 10:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Collections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a list of Videos i&#8217;ve watched in the past and found worth sharing. Why You Are Lonely and How to Make Friends&#160;–&#160;Pandemic has decreased [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="height:26px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h6>Here&#8217;s a list of Videos i&#8217;ve watched in the past and found worth sharing.</h6>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Why You Are Lonely and How to Make Friends</a>&nbsp;–&nbsp;Pandemic has decreased social interactions than before, limiting mostly to virtual connects. This video explains why it&#8217;s important that we seek out friends and social connections and practical tips of how to go about it.</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eW6Eagr9XA" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">The 4 things it takes to be an expert</a> – <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/subhadip-panja-28612a18/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><strong>Subhadip</strong> </a>recommended Veritasium a couple months back and I&#8217;ve since then become a fan of their videos. In this video, Dr. Derek talks about the 4 things that are required to become an expert at things and why you can’t have expert in every field</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=biNMRQJXvfs" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Why No One Can Agree What’s REALLY the Tallest Mountain</a> – Did you know that the longest mountain range in earth is under sea and the tallest peak isn&#8217;t necessarily the Everest? There&#8217;s never a time when I have come out of a video from this channel without learning something new and also wondering how some of the simplest things we assume from our schooling can actually be very complex.</li><li>As someone who personally struggles with initiating the first conversation, I found <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F4Zu5ZZAG7I" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">7 Ways to Make a Conversation with Anyone</a> very insightful and practical. It’s a beautiful TEDx talk that you’ll appreciate if you are working to get better at connecting and talking to someone.</li><li>**<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2A7mblg5UKc" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Trying to Land a Plane (to Prove a Point)</a> **- <em>I’ve always been intrigued by Dunning-Krueger effect &amp; Imposter Syndrome and how it pretty much manifests in everybody. Personally I’m starting to get comfortable saying “I Don’t Know” and “I need help” more often these days.</em></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEENEFaVUzU" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">The Last Human! &#8211; A Glimpse into the Far Future</a> &#8211; I’ve always been mesmerized by Futurism. It expands your own thought process of what’s possible and how to think about things. It opens your mind to the various possibilities of handling situations not only in the future but also in the present.</li><li>* <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=30vTc1SOt_w" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Sensory Adaptation!</a> &#8211; Without this very strange phenomenon, you would be lost, overwhelmed, and completely unable to navigate the external world.</li><li>* <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F-nNTGK0wFw" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Unanswered &#8211; Mysteries from the Mahabharata | Christopher Charles Doyle | TEDxYouth@NMS</a></li><li>* <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6syj1PWMDLM" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Did Ancient India have AI Robot Technology?</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=75d_29QWELk" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Change your Life, one step at a time</a> : I’m a big fan of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/inanutshell" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Kurzgesagt</a> videos and highly recommend it. This one came exactly when I was thinking of making some small changes in my lifestyle. I’ve been awe-inspired by the amount of research that goes behind making some of these videos. <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/sources-change/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Here&#8217;s</a> the supplementary info for this particular video.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Articles</title>
		<link>/2022/09/10/articles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 10:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Collections]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a list of articles i&#8217;ve found interesting Chesterton&#8217;s Fence &#8211; A Lesson in Second Order Thinking – As Modernization, Reorganization, Consolidation etc. become part [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="height:20px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h6>Here&#8217;s a list of articles i&#8217;ve found interesting</h6>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://fs.blog/chestertons-fence/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Chesterton&#8217;s Fence &#8211; A Lesson in Second Order Thinking</a> – As Modernization, Reorganization, Consolidation etc. become part of our usual work vocabulary, it’s imperative we understand the importance of second order thinking. As the article points out &#8221; <em>A core component of making great decisions is understanding the rationale behind previous decisions. If we don’t understand how we got “here,” we run the risk of making things much worse</em> &#8220;</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://jamesclear.com/why-facts-dont-change-minds" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Why Facts Don&#8217;t change Minds</a> – “ <em>The way to change people’s minds is to become friends with them, to integrate them into your tribe, to bring them into your circle. Now, they can change their beliefs without the risk of being abandoned socially</em> &#8221; &#8211; In this article, James talks about why facts don&#8217;t usually change minds and what does it take to get people to accept a different point of view</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/lifestyles/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Lifestyles &#8211; Morgan Housel</a> – A well written piece that talks about how important mindsets are and how finding a balance between external vs internal measures of success or happiness are core to our wellbeing.</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://blog.pragmaticengineer.com/a-team-where-everyone-is-a-leader/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">An Engineering team where everyone is a leader</a> – A very well written piece with practical tips for managers and leaders on how to build a team where each engineer is empowered to make decisions and leads from the front.</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/07/16/1028580/pandemic-mental-health-new-normal/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">How to mend your broken pandemic brain</a> – COVID-19 pandemic has truly hit the humankind in all possible areas including messing up our brains. As the world slowly starts its recovery journey, this article talks about some of the impacts to our brain and how we can help fix it faster.</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32226910" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Ask HN: I&#8217;m in a rut. How did you get out of yours?</a> – This active thread on HackerNews has lot of tips and discussions on how to handle and recover from Burnout and languishing. What intrigued me was, how a simple question when asked in a powerful forum could lead to tons of learning. Never be afraid to ask questions!</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-can-i-become-director-guru-bhat/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">How can I become a Director?</a> – A very well written piece by Guru Bhat on what it takes to become a director. Eloquent as always, Guru hits the bulls eye on some key attributes that everyone should aspire to attain if they are on a quest for this title. I’ve been fortunate to learn by experience how “Bias for Action” can be a key differentiator in creating value for our stakeholders.</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/07/12/1055773/crispr-gene-editing-cholesterol/" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">Injections that edit Genes to stop diseases!</a> – I’m filled with both hope and fear when I read articles like this. While this has the power to save millions of people, what stops someone from using the same tech for nefarious purposes.</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"><strong></strong></a><strong><a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90596343/how-to-work-with-someone-you-cant-stand" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">How to work with someone you can’t stand</a> –</strong> “ <em>Like it or not, your job and reputation can rely on an ability to get along with others.”</em> Valdes-Dapena says there are steps you can take to make the situation more bearable.”</li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9hJ_Rux9y0" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer"></a><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/top.html" data-wpel-link="external" target="_blank" rel="external noopener noreferrer">The Top Idea in your mind</a> – Another one of those gems from Tim’s newsletter where Paul Graham writes about ambient thought.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
