<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Friday Musings &#8211; Infinite Possibilities</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/mySite/category/friday-musings/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Dare to Dream</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 07:12:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 22/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/22/friday-musings-22-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 05:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Articles I’m reading. How can I become a Director? &#160;– A very well written piece by Guru Bhat on what it takes to become a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-3 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-1 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Articles I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-can-i-become-director-guru-bhat/">How can I become a Director? </a>&nbsp;– A very well written piece by Guru Bhat on what it takes to become a director. Eloquent as always, Guru hits the bulls eye on some key attributes that everyone should aspire to attain if they are on a quest for this title. I’ve been fortunate to learn by experience how “Bias for Action” can be a key differentiator in creating value for our stakeholders.</p>



<h3><strong><em>What worries me!</em></strong></h3>



<p>It’s hard to miss the series of natural calamities rocking the already pandemic struck world right now. From the <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2022/07/19/google_oracle_cloud/?mc_cid=1674b3c928&amp;mc_eid=2b8cf1fb98">extreme heat waves in UK &amp; Europe</a> to <a href="https://www.thenationalnews.com/world/asia/2022/07/21/indias-monsoon-havoc-a-result-of-climate-change-experts-say/">Cloud bursts and Flash floods in India</a>, It’s time each one of us do our part to slow down climate change. <a href="https://medium.com/@cinthia.espino/why-is-0-5-c-so-important-3961b9989387">Read this</a> if you want to know what a 0.5° Celsius change could mean to earth and <a href="https://coastal.climatecentral.org/map/10/72.9068/18.9721/?theme=sea_level_rise&amp;map_type=year&amp;basemap=roadmap&amp;contiguous=true&amp;elevation_model=best_available&amp;forecast_year=2040&amp;pathway=ssp3rcp70&amp;percentile=p50&amp;refresh=true&amp;return_level=return_level_0&amp;rl_model=gtsr&amp;slr_model=ipcc_2021_med">see these projections</a> of cities that would be under water if the sea-levels continues to rise.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://tim.blog/2022/06/28/edward-o-thorp-2/">Master Investor Ed Thorp on How to think for yourself and many more topics</a> – This is a long format podcast but there&#8217;s some invaluable takeaways from Ed&#8217;s experience. I&#8217;m a big fan of the Tim&#8217;s questions to his guests and the insights that he gleans from them. What particularly excited me in this podcast was how Ed was leveraging the power of compounding in anything he does, be it investing, loosing weight, forming habits, learning new things etc. Really loved the concept of &#8220;scrap time&#8221; and hope to incorporate in my life as well.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://wasp-lang.dev/blog/2022/06/24/ML-code-gen-vs-coding-by-hand-future">ML Codegen Vs Coding by Hand</a> – In the previous musings I shared about auto code-gen and it got me intrigued into aspects that are debatable and why we should tread with care. This post explores some of this nuance and has a good further reading on other thoughts on the same topic as well</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>If you really think that the environment is less important than the economy, try holding your breath while you count your money</p><cite>Guy McPherson</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-2 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings 15/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/15/friday-musings-15-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 05:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Article I’m reading. Injections that edit Genes to stop diseases! – I’m filled with both hope and fear when I read articles like this. While [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-6 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-4 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Article I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/07/12/1055773/crispr-gene-editing-cholesterol/">Injections that edit Genes to stop diseases!</a> – I’m filled with both hope and fear when I read articles like this. While this has the power to save millions of people, what stops someone from using the same tech for nefarious purposes.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Places I’ve travelled.</em></strong></h3>



<p>I was in Bangalore this week meeting my colleagues in-person in office and wow, what a week it was. While there’s comfort &amp; some flexibility in working from home, nothing can beat the in-person collaboration and getting things done quickly. For me, Video calls somehow reduce the personal &amp; emotional side of the conversation. Looking forward to many more such visits and catching up with my people!</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/why-youre-smarter-than-you-think/">Why you&#8217;re smarter than you think!</a> – From the Hidden brain show notes – “<em>From the time we are schoolchildren, we are ranked and sorted based on how smart we are. But what if our assumptions about intelligence limit our potential? This week, psychologist Scott Barry Kaufman proposes a more expansive notion of what it means to be “smart</em>&#8220;.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><em> </em></strong><a href="https://simonwillison.net/2022/Jul/9/gpt-3-explain-code/">Can GPT-3 explain how code works?</a> – I was amazed by the extent to which models like GPT-3 &amp; OpenAI Codex are getting increasingly efficient at writing code. Makes me wonder when we’d land in a situation where we no longer hire programmers</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>You wouldn&#8217;t worry so much about what others think of you if you realized how seldom they do</p><cite>Elenaor Roosevelt</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-5 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 08/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/08/friday-musings-08-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 04:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Article I’m reading. How to work with someone you can’t stand – “Like it or not, your job and reputation can rely on an ability [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<div class="wp-container-9 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-7 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<h3><strong><em>Article I’m reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90596343/how-to-work-with-someone-you-cant-stand">How to work with someone you can’t stand</a> –</strong>  “<em>Like it or not, your job and reputation can rely on an ability to get along with others.”</em> Valdes-Dapena says there are steps you can take to make the situation more bearable.”</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2A7mblg5UKc">Trying to Land a Plane (to Prove a Point)</a> &nbsp;</strong>&#8211; <em>I’ve always been intrigued by Dunning-Krueger effect &amp; Imposter Syndrome and how it pretty much manifests in everybody. Personally I’m starting to get comfortable saying “I Don’t Know” and “I need help” more often these days.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://freakonomics.com/podcast/how-simple-is-too-simple/"><strong>How simple is too simple</strong></a> –<em> In this episode of “No Stupid Questions”, Angela Duckworth and Stephen Dubner discuss the obsession humans have with magic bullet solutions and why there are no simple answers.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings&nbsp;</em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.morling.dev/blog/whats-in-a-good-error-message/">What&#8217;s in a good Error Message</a>? </strong>– <em>Extremely important for all engineering devs and leads reviewing code. Both the article and the discussion/comments following it has several extremely using nuggets we should think about.</em></p>



<h3><strong><em>Quote I’m thinking about!</em></strong> </h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“What is Common Sense, isn’t Common Practice” – Stephen Covey</p></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-8 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 01/Jul/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/07/01/friday-musings-01-jul-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Books I’m (re)reading. I’ve picked up “Radical Candor” by Kim Scott again. IMO, it’s one of the must reads for anyone picking up Management for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-12 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-10 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Books I’m (re)reading.</em></strong></h3>



<p>I’ve picked up <a href="https://www.radicalcandor.com/the-book/">“Radical Candor” by Kim Scott</a> again. IMO, it’s one of the must reads for anyone picking up Management for their career. It shows managers how to be successful while retaining their humanity, finding meaning in their job, and creating an environment where people both love their work and their colleagues</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEENEFaVUzU">The Last Human! &#8211; A Glimpse into&nbsp; the Far Future</a> &nbsp;&#8211; I’ve always been mesmerized by Futurism. It expands your own thought process of what’s possible and how to think about things. It opens your mind to the various possibilities of handling situations not only in the future but also in the present.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/KmhQvIwN">How to Change Your Workplace</a> – Adam Grant’s “Work Life” has been one of my all-time favorite podcasts and in this episode he delves into “Change” and how each one of us no matter where we are in the hierarchy can bring about meaningful, positive, long-lasting change and motivate people to embrace new ideas.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://cachelib.org/learnmore/">CacheLib</a> – Facebook’s web scale general purpose caching engine that powers multiple critical applications.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I did not succeed in Life because of Intelligence, I Succeeded because I have a long attention span</p><cite>Charlie Munger</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-11 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 24/Jun/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/06/24/friday-musings-24-jun-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Short stories I’m (re)reading I’ve been deeply inspired by some of these stories and it has stuck with me and has changed the way I [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-15 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-13 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Short stories I’m (re)reading</em></strong></h3>



<p>I’ve been deeply inspired by some of <a href="https://www.klib.in/short-life-stories/">these stories</a> and it has stuck with me and has changed the way I think and act.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=30vTc1SOt_w">Sensory Adaptation!</a> &nbsp;&#8211; Without this very strange phenomenon, you would be lost, overwhelmed, and completely unable to navigate the external world.</li></ul>



<h3><strong><em>Documentaries I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bFCOm1P_cQQ">The Brain that changes itself</a> – Our Brain is fantastic and continues to amaze researchers trying to unlock its secrets. You would’ve heard people say Change is hard and most people hate change, but if you look deep, your body and specifically your Brain is tuned efficiently adapt, handle and thrive with continuous changes.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><em> </em></strong><a href="https://neuralink.com/blog/monkey-mindpong/">Mind Pong!</a> – I’m so excited to see how tech like these will change our future and the things we’ll be able to accomplish. While a part of this brings hope, there’s fear on what this would do in the wrong hands.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Isn’t it a Paradox that we want a newer version of everything, but we fear to change our mind?</p><cite>Carmen Jacob</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-14 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 17/Jun/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/06/17/friday-musings-17-jun-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Places I visited I was fortunate this week to visit two historic temple sites in Tamilnadu, the Chidambaram Nataraja Temple and Vaithayanatha Swamy Temple in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-18 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-16 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Places I visited</em></strong></h3>



<p>I was fortunate this week to visit two historic temple sites in Tamilnadu, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nataraja_Temple,_Chidambaram">the Chidambaram Nataraja Temple</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vaitheeswaran_Koil">Vaithayanatha Swamy Temple</a> in VaitheeswaranKoil. It&#8217;s amazing to see the architectural marvels on these temples &#8211; thousands of carved stone pillars and replicas without a single imperfection. I&#8217;m not sure if one can achieve such a feat even with the latest scientific tools we have at our disposal now. Chidambaram Temple (more specifically the feet of Swamy Nataraja in the temple) is also believed to be the <a href="https://ramanisblog.in/2015/04/06/chidambaram-geomagnetic-centre-of-earth-universe-study/">center point of Earth&#8217;s Magnetic equator.</a> While recent estimations put the temple ~2 degrees off the magnetic equator, given the magnetic fields fluctuate, it may really have been accurate when the original temple was constructed.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Documentaries I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GYHu0ivfR_o">Ancient Aliens &#8211; Puzzling Pillars</a> – Temple pillars that can sing and reverberate. No existing technology can easily reproduce these ancient marvels at the scale it was done. One wonders, where&#8217;s all that lost knowledge from Ancient India. While I’ve still not visited Hampi, i was personally fortunate to experience the sounds from these stone pillars that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nellaiappar_Temple">Sri Nellayappar Temple in Tirunelveli</a>.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos that Kindled Curiosity</em></strong></h3>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F-nNTGK0wFw">Unanswered &#8211; Mysteries from the Mahabharata | Christopher Charles Doyle | TEDxYouth@NMS</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6syj1PWMDLM">Did Ancient India have AI Robot Technology?</a></li></ul>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/05/23/openai-look-at-our-awesome-image-generator-google-hold-my-shiba-inu/">Google Imagen</a> &#8211; What is original / real / true? With tech like GPT-3, Imagen etc, answering questions like this, fact checking news articles, authenticating artwork will get increasingly difficult with expanding AI prowess.</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Life is what happens to you while you’re busy making other plans.</p><cite>Allen Saunders</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-17 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Musings &#8211; 10/Jun/2022</title>
		<link>/2022/06/10/friday-musings-10-jun-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vikram Ramakrishnan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 07:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Friday Musings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Podcasts I’m listening to Mind Reading 2.0: Why Conversations go wrong hosted by Shankar Vedantam (@HiddenBrain) where they talk about conversational styles and why understanding [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-container-21 wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-container-19 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:66.66%">
<div style="height:14px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h3><strong><em>Podcasts I’m listening to</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://hiddenbrain.org/podcast/why-conversations-go-wrong/">Mind Reading 2.0: Why Conversations go wrong</a> hosted by Shankar Vedantam (<a href="https://twitter.com/HiddenBrain">@HiddenBrain</a>) where they talk about conversational styles and why understanding them is important to be able to effectively communicate.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Articles I’m reading</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/top.html">The Top Idea in your mind</a> – Another one of those gems from Tim’s newsletter where Paul Graham writes about ambient thought.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Videos I’m watching</em></strong></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=75d_29QWELk">Change your Life, one step at a time</a> : I’m a big fan of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/inanutshell">Kurzgesagt</a> videos and highly recommend it. This one came exactly when I was thinking of making some small changes in my lifestyle. I’ve been awe-inspired by the amount of research that goes behind making some of these videos. <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/sources-change/">Here&#8217;s</a> the supplementary info for this particular video.</p>



<h3><strong><em>Tech Readings </em></strong></h3>



<p><strong><em> </em></strong><a href="https://makersacademy.medium.com/what-is-rubber-duck-debugging-d3028d70a707">Rubber Duck Debugging</a>. I never knew what I used occasionally as a Developer in the early days had a name and real psychology behind it!</p>



<h3><em>Quote I&#8217;m thinking about</em></h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>One Man’s Terrorist is another’s man Freedom Fighter</p><cite>Anon</cite></blockquote>
</div>



<div class="wp-container-20 wp-block-column" style="flex-basis:33.33%">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://cdn.mcauto-images-production.sendgrid.net/954c252fedab403f/698868b9-830d-4c42-a9f1-087b4b05c13e/422x463.png" alt=""/></figure>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
